Finding Aid for the Louise LeQuire Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Louise LeQuire Papers
2017
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0887
11.7 Linear Feet
Biographical Sketch
Louise Lasseter LeQuire (1924-2006) was a longtime teacher, artist, and curator in Nashville, Tennessee. A graduate of Peabody College, she taught Studio Art and Art History at Montgomery Bell Academy and the Tennessee Institute for the Arts. She also served as the first Art Critic for the Nashville Bannerx as a regular contributor from 1951-1960.
In addition to her teaching and art journalism, LeQuire served many municipal and state organizations such as the Metro Nashville Arts Commission and the Visual Arts Alliance of Nashville in her effort to promote art patronage in Nashville and Tennessee.. A great deal of her collection contains documents and correspondence from her years with these various organizations.
A lifelong Nashville resident, she was married to Dr. Virgil LeQuire, a doctor at Vanderbilt Medical Center, and was mother to four children: Nancy, Paul, Alan, and Lista. Alan is now known for his sculpture work in Nashville, particularly for his “Athena Parthenos” at the Nashville Parthenon and his “Musica,” which serves as the centerpiece of Music City Circle.
LeQuire passed away on July 30, 2006 after a long battle with cancer.
Scope and Content Note
The Louise LeQuire Papers are composed of 11.7 linear feet of research, writings, correspondence and photographs from her career as an artist, curator, writer and teacher. The dates of the collection range from the 1950s to the early 2000s and contain much of LeQuire’s own work as well as extensive research on notable artists of the time
LeQuire was also a tireless advocate for individual artists in the Nashville community, and her collection reflects that interest through its substantial files on individual artists. LeQuire wrote heavily on William Edmonson’s sculpture work, including a publication in Smithsonian magazine in 1985. LeQuire was also an advocate for Red Grooms and Frederic Remington, about whom she produced films. Her Red Grooms film, Sunflower in a Hothouse, was nominated for an Academy award in 1987.
Career—includes LeQuire’s materials on her art career, divided into subsections by type of work
Organizations—details on the many commissions and other organizations on which LeQuire served
Writing—drafts and final copies of news and magazine articles or lectures given by LeQuire
Teaching—teaching resources LeQuire used, correspondence with other faculty, and information on schools LeQuire supported
Curation—correspondence and artist profiles used in LeQuire’s curation work for, among other groups, corporate firms and the Nashville airport
Art—Exhibitions—images and inventories from LeQuire’s own art shows, which primarily showed watercolors and landscapes
Art—Portraits— images and correspondence from LeQuire’s private portrait commissions
Research
Gallery/Venue Research—brochures and news clippings regarding galleries and venues across the nation, with emphasis on Nashville and New York City
Subject Research—news clippings and academic resources on various art movements, such as the Harlem Renaissance, Southern Art, and Women in the Arts
Family
Virgil LeQuire—personal details from and about LeQuire’s husband, Virgil, and his career and colleagues at the Vanderbilt Medical Center and Vanderbilt Medical School
Alan LeQuire—news clippings, correspondence, and other materials regarding LeQuire’s son, Alan, with specific emphasis on his “Athena” at the Nashville Parthenon
Rollin Lasseter—writings by and news clippings about LeQuire’s brother Rollin, who primarily wrote and published short stories
Artist Research
Poets—writings by various poets within and outside of the Nashville community of interest to LeQuire, including Ezra Pound
Red Grooms—correspondence, biographical information, and exhibit information and photos pertaining to Red Grooms
William Edmondson—research about Edmondson’s sculptures and correspondence regarding the use and distribution of Edmondson’s work
Other Artists—individual files continuing information and/or correspondence regarding different artists within and outside of the Nashville community
Media Materials
Pertaining to Donald Davie: Poet as Sculptor
Provenance Statement
This collection was donated by Louise LeQuire and her family to Vanderbilt Special Collections in 2012.
Literary Rights Statement
Permission to publish, copy, reprint, digitize, orally record for transmission over public or private airways, or use material from the Louise LeQuire Papers in any and all other current or future developed methods or procedures, must be obtained in writing from the Special Collections and University Archives Division of the Vanderbilt University Libraries. All rights are reserved and retained regardless of current or future development or laws that may apply to fair use standards.
- Career
  - LeQuire Biographies (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum Vitae (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Honors, Clippings/Correspondences (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs—Personal (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Louise (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence—Personal (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence—Personal (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Nashville Banner—About LeQuire (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - LeQuire Collection of Tennessee Artists (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Expenses, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Supply Catalogs (1) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Supply Catalogs (2) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Art—Contracts (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nashville Artist Guild, 1952-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Nashville Arts Council, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Nashville Artist Guild Slides, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Nashville Artist Guild, 1989-2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Organization
  - Nashville Artist Guild, News Clippings, 1959-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Nashville Artist Guild, Gallery, News Clippings, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Nashville Artist Guild, News Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Nashville Artist Guild, website (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Nashville Artist Guild, newsletters (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Arts, Education, and Americans Panel, Memphis, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nashville Academy of Sciences Panel, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Tennessee Arts Commission, Arts Report, 1979-1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Tennessee Arts Commission, news clippings (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Tennessee Arts Commission, letter to Governor Alexander (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Tennessee Arts Commission, letter to Governor Sundquist (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Tennessee Arts Commission, nomination of LeQuire for Governor’s Award (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Nashville Arts, Summer Lights, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Metro Nashville Arts Commission, 1979, letter from Mayor Fulton (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Metro Nashville Arts Commission, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Metro Nashville Arts Commission, Reports, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Metro Nashville Arts Commission, 1995 “Arts Alert” (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Metro Nashville Arts Commission, letter to The Nashville Banner (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Nashville Institute for the Arts, 1981-1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - MBA Festival for the Arts, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Tennessee Writers’ Alliance, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Nashville Institute for the Arts, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Nashville Arts Summit, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Nashville Institute for the Arts, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Nashville Agenda’s Action Team on the Arts (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Williamson County Arts Council (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - VAAN Newsletters (1) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - VAAN Newsletters (2) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - VAAN Forums (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - VAAN, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - VAAN Education Committee, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - VAAN, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - VAAN Education Committee, 1993 (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - VAAN Education Committee, 1993 (2) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - VAAN, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - VAAN Education Committee, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - VAAN Arts Rag (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - VAAN, 1995 (1) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - VAAN, 1995 (2) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - VAANGuard Gallery, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - VAAN, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - VAAN Board Meeting, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - VAAN, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - VAAN, no date (1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - VAAN, no date (2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - VAAN Education Committee, no date (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Book Club (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Book Club—Papers Written (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - National Book Club Award Winners (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Book Club—Secondary Reading (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Book Club—Pictures of Members (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Writing
  - Nashville Life Article, December/January 1996 (1)—all materials (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Nashville Life Article, December/January 1996 (2)—all materials (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Nashville Life Article, December/January 1996 (3)—all materials (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Poem, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Nashville Banner Clippings, 1954-1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - LeQuire’s “Europe” Series in The Nashville Banner, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Nashville Banner Clippings, 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Nashville Banner Clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lecture, “Twentieth Century Sculpture in America,”, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Tennessean Magazine, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Essay, Twentieth Century Sculpture in America, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Motive Magazine, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Memoir of, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Nashville Magazine, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Sublett Paper (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Christian Home, 1966-68 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Lecture, “On Poetry and Painting…Some Contingencies Examined,”, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Report to the Panel on the Arts, Education and Americans, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Éguilles Article, Food Magazine, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Nashville Magazine, November 1979 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Nashville Magazine, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Middle Tennessee Conference/Lecture, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Smithsonian, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - APSU Conference, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - The Tennessean, Letter to the Editor, May 9, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Vanderbilt Magazine, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Teaching
  - MBA Clippings (1) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - MBA Clippings (2) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - MBA Xanadu (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - MBA Collection of Work, “The Blue Guitar” (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - MBA Graduation Speech, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dedication of LeQuire Room (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cheekwood Lecture, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Peabody College European Tour, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Middle Tennessee Teachers’ Workshop, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Cheekwood Workshop, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - TN Arts Academy (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Robert Pletcher, Metro Arts Education (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Harpeth Hall School (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The Watkins Institute (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Workshops (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - News Clippings (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Curation
  - Nashville Arts Festival, Programs, 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence—Mayor Fulton, Incoming, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Nashville Century II (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Nashville Century III (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Nashville Artists/Photos for Century III (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Nashville Century III—News Clippings (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Airport Authority Collection—Potential Purchase Information (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Airport Authority Collection—Artist resumes (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Nashville Arts Festival—News Clippings (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Misc. Exhibit entries (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Farris, Warfield, and Kanaday Collection (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Farris, Warfield, and Kanaday Collection —Correspondence, outgoing (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Farris, Warfield, and Kanaday Collection —Correspondence, incoming (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Farris, Warfield, and Kanaday Collection—Resumes (1) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Farris, Warfield, and Kanaday Collection—Resumes (2) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Farris, Warfield, and Kanaday Collection—Artist Photos (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Farris, Warfield, and Kanaday Collection—Article on Corporate Art Patronage (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Richard Florshem Art Fund (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Art—Exhibitions
  - Exhibitions—Lists of Works (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Women’s Visions Gallery Membership Application (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Shows/Competitions—Nashville (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence—APSU, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Mère Bulles Exhibition, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Exhibit, Cheekwood Pineapple Room, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - University Club Show (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition at Wild Iris, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Harpeth Hall, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Harpeth Hall, Images (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Cheekwood, A Century of Progress, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Cheekwood, A Century of Progress, 2002, news clippings (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Joint Exhibits with Family (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Joint Exhibits with Others (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - “Woods and a Pond” at Nashville Artists Guild, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous notes and sketches (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous exhibition photos (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Postcards by LeQuire (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Church of the Advent, Episcopal, Program by LeQuire (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - News Clippings (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Art—Portraits
  - Lamar Alexander—Photographs (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Lamar Alexander—Photographs (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Lamar Alexander—Photographs (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Lamar Alexander—Photographs (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Lamar Alexander—Photographs (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Lamar Alexander—Photographs (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Lamar Alexander—Photographs (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Lamar Alexander—Photographs (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Lamar Alexander—Photographs and Negatives (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Lamar Alexander—News Clippings (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Article on LeQuire’s portraits, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Portraits at Vanderbilt (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - “Distinctive Women of Tennessee” Exhibit at TN Historical Society, featuring portraits (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Portrait Photographs and Negatives, unnamed (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Portrait Photographs and Negatives, unnamed (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Portrait Photographs of Susan Heiskell Wilkes and family (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Portrait of Governor Wallace (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Portrait of Albert Brewer (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Portrait Photographs of Enid Katahn, Blair School of Music (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Portrait Photographs and Negatives, unnamed (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Portrait Photographs and Negatives, unnamed (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Portrait Photographs and Negatives, unnamed (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Portrait Photographs and Negatives, unnamed (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Presentations of Rollo Park’s portrait, April 1991 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Portrait Photographs and Negatives, unnamed (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Portrait Photographs and Negatives, unnamed (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Portrait Photographs and Negatives, unnamed (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Portrait Photographs and Negatives, unnamed (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Portrait Photographs and Negatives, unnamed (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Postcards (Portraits) (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Research
  - Exhibition/Venue Research
    - Fisk (General Info) (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, incoming, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Photographs, Stieglitz (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Stieglitz Collection Catalogs (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Stieglitz, Night Photography (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Teacher’s Guide for Stieglitz Collection (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - News Clippings, Stieglitz Collection, 1946-1996 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - News Clippings, Stieglitz Collection, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - “Works on Paper,” Van Vechten Gallery, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Generations in Black and White (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Film Negatives, no date (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - News Clippings, Fisk/Van Vechten Gallery, 1978-1995 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - News Clippings, Fisk/Van Vechten Gallery, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - News Clippings, Fisk/Van Vechten Gallery, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, War Memorial Building as new State Art Museum (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Frist Museum, creation of (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - TSU Exhibits (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Tennessee State Museum (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Cheekwood Exhibit Guides/Catalogs (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Tennessee Venues (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Tennessee Museum Exhibitions/Brochures (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Nashville Exhibits/Brochures (1) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Nashville Exhibits/Brochures (2) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Zeitgeist Gallery (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - News Clippings about Nashville Shows (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Nashville Theater/Music (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - New Orleans Museum of Art (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Texas/Kimball Art Museum (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Alabama Artists Gallery, New Deal Era Art (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Bass Hall, Fort Worth—News Clippings (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Religious Arts Festival, Second Presbyterian Church, Little Rock, Arkansas (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Austin Community College Art—Ridgeview (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Delaplaine Visual Arts Center, Maryland (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Los Angeles Museum of Art (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - New York City Museum Exhibitions/Brochures (1) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - New York City Museum Exhibitions/Brochures (2) (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - New York City Museum Exhibitions/Brochures (3) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - “The Cathedral of Commerce”—Woolworth Building, New York City (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Greenwich Village Artists Club (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Postcards from New York City Museums (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Washington, D.C. Museums (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Washington, D.C. Museum Exhibitions/Brochures (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, Incoming, Smithsonian Museum, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Art Institute of Chicago (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Tarquinia Collection (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous Museum Exhibitions/Brochures (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Subject Research
    - Historic South (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Historic Tennessee (1 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Historic Tennessee (2 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Historic Nashville (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Nashville Architecture/Development (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Nashville Architecture/Development (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Nashville Architecture/Development (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Nashville Architecture Book (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Nashville Planet Hollywood (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Pearl-Cohn High School (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Marathon Village, Nashville (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - National Museum of Women in the Arts, Newsletter, Summer 1988 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Women in the Arts, Spring 1995 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Women in the Arts, Summer 1995 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Women in the Arts, Summer 1996 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Women in the Arts, Summer 1999 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Women in the Arts, Clippings (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Women in the Arts, Book Review of Women Artists and the Surrealist Movement (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Women in the Arts, notes (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Women in the Arts, National Museum of American Art exhibit (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Women in the Arts, news clippings (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Female Artists in ArtNews (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Women’s History Month (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Female Art Brochures/Exhibits (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Greek Art (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Native American Art (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - African American Art Bibliography (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - African American History Guides (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - African American Art Exhibitions (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - African Art (Entremont Antique), 1973 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Nashville and the Harlem Renaissance, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Brodsky & Treadway’s Super 8 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Article, “Best of the West” (western sculpture) (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Article, Discover, “How to Heal a Masterpiece,”, April 1999 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Curation/Preservation (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Article, ArtNews, “The American Action Painters,”, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Portfolio Article, American Impressionism (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Portfolio Article, English Watercolors (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Portfolio Article, American Watercolors (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - No: An Independent Quarterly of the Visual Arts, winter 1996 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - The Tennessee Millennium—, July 4, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Tennessee Conservationist, Sept/Oct 1985 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Nashville Magazine, April 1967 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Vanderbilt Alumnus, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Vanderbilt Magazine, Spring 1998 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Circle, Belmont University, Winter 1999 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Punch Magazine (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Art&Man Papers (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Art&Man Booklets (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Canticle, Issue #4 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Ceramics Catalog (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Cooking—recipes and clippings (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - News Clippings, Art, general (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Hollywood Movie Photos (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Vanderbilt (Box 13, Folder 25)
- Family
  - Virgil LeQuire
    - Virgil (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - American Indian in Tennessee (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Goats (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Rabbits (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Letter on 47th Anniversary, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Who’s Who in Williamson, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - The Physician’s Guide to Leisure (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Schizophrenic Arts, Billing (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Vanderbilt Department of Psychiatry (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Vanderbilt University School of Medicine/VUMC (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Vanderbilt—VUMC (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Alan LeQuire
    - CV/Resumes (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Catalogs/Pamphlets (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - MBA (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Music Row Statue (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Demonbreun Statue on Cumberland (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Vietnam Memorial by Alan, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Musica, News Clippings (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Misc. Sculpture, News Clippings (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - LeQuire Gallery Newsletters (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, France, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Exhibitions (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - “Sale of Art” Receipts/Records/Checks (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Athena/Parthenon (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Athena/Parthenon (2) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Athena Archetype (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Athena News Clippings (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Athena News Clippings (2) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, outgoing, Athena Fund Foundation (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, incoming, Athena Fund Foundation (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Athena Fund Foundation (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Booklets on Parthenon/Athena (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Writing on Art, Meaning, Parthenon, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - The Sculpting of Athena, film (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Athena Smiles, Context/Art (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Athena Smiles, Draft (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Athena Smiles, Watercolor (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Parthenon Patrons (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Versus, October 1983 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Vanderbilt Alumnus, vol 70 no 1, Winter 1984 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Nashville!, May 1990 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - American Arts Quarterly, Spring 2001 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Rollin Lasseter
    - Rollin Letters (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Letters, 1964-1996 (Box 16, Folder 2)